# **Greetings**

I am a simplifier, I love making things easier for anyone I can help. Whether it's an intuitive architecture to improve maintainability, automating tasks for coworkers, simplifying content management for clients, or creating fast & pleasant experiences for users. I even seek ways to simplify my wife's daily tasks, researching solutions for my friends out of curiosity, or setting up technical devices for my parents to minimize complexities. At the core of what makes me an exceptional front-end developer is the desire to help others by creating an enjoyable experience.

I am a design-centric developer focused on quality products, not settling for "good enough". I love working with great designers that can focus on their art, and they enjoy working with me for my level of care and attention when bringing their designs to life. I'm proactive in implementing the look and feel that they've created across the site, resulting in less back-and-forth, less meetings, and a greater ROI for the business. I'm independently driven to get my work done and favor having a team to collaborate for advice with a new feature or tackling different obstacles on the same project.

# **Aspirations**

I am searching for a work place that is looking ahead. One that's able to meet the needs of a product with the ability to adapt to the constant changes in the industry. One that's moving forward with emerging technology as well as workplace environment. A place to collaborate with a team that strives to push each other forward, learning new technologies that help us deliver a better product and increase productivity.

I love what I do and easily work more than required. Every project is a new opportunity to learn, and I want to grow my talents to expand my skillset.



502.802.8924 timbomckay@gmail.com

## **Skills**

- WordPress + ACF
- JS + VueJS & jQuery
- CSS + SASS, LESS & Stylus
- Atomic Design
- SVG Assets
- User Focused Functionality
- Responsive Minded
- Performance Optimization
- Cross-browser Compatibility
- Pixel Perfectionist
- Readability Research
- Workflow Efficiency

## **Tools**

- Bootstrap & Foundation
  Frameworks
- Laravel Valet
- SublimeText & Atom
- Adobe Creative Suite CC
- Webpack 4
- Git + GitFlow

## **Experience**

## Blackstone Media March 2017 - May 2018

#### Front-End Architect

Leading a team in creating a VueJS E-Commerce application for a Fortune 10 company, as well as converting their website to a VueJS based WordPress theme. Constructing custom and intuitive page building systems. Guiding designers in atomic design to aid development and challenging developers to write efficient, maintainable code.

### Mission Data March 2015 - February 2017

### Web Designer & Front-End Developer

Designing & developing websites and applications for various organizations in many environments, including Ruby on Rails and PHP. Creating responsive websites featuring video integration from multiple providers and utilizing SVGs for crisp, scaleable graphics. Creating responsive styles for fonts to adjust sizes based on window size and implementing JSON data to populate tv series listings.

## Net Tango June 2012 - February 2015

### Web Designer & Front-End Developer

Designing websites for clients in various industries, including healthcare, city government and point-of-sale sites. Using Google Maps & Charts api to create concepts to demonstrate tourism and data reports.

#### Freelance September 2006 - Present

#### Multimedia Designer/Developer

Initially a graphics designer eventually venturing into web development and tinkering with photography & videography as needed.

# **Education**

## ITT-Technical Institute August 2005 - May 2007

## Associates of Applied Science in Multimedia

A curriculum which introduced a variety of programs dealing with 3D modeling, video editing, graphic design, and web development.